Rural health care is definitely different,
um,
so it's sometimes very hard to find providers who will go out and,
uh,
work in that environment
and so as a physician you find yourself again doing a lot that you
may not do in a bigger setting you definitely feel part of that community,
uh,
so having that access,
having the ability for,
um,
patients to be able to just walk right down and come in and be seen.
Uh,
again,
for a variety,
not only primary care but for mental health needs,
for dental needs,
um,
is huge for the rule setting.
There's lots of influences to our health outside of the science that goes on and so,
um,
I really love.
Practicing in a community health center because
we can really address the issues that influence whole health in a really robust way
we're able to
address the behavioral health,
emotional health,
as well as the social determinants of health that really.
Um,
drive a lot of the,
uh,
disease states that we see.
I think it's really,
uh,
refreshing to practice in a community health center.
There's a whole network of community health centers across our state,
and there's a lot of collaboration between the centers,
and that's something I never really realized existed.
Um,
I think primary health.
Care and community health centers in general are kind of a hidden gem
in the world of medicine
we have
in each health center based upon
the
community need,
many of us have dental partners we have brain health
partners so
that
in one
visit.
In one center
you can address a multitude
of what
healthcare means.
Along with the notion of team-based care,
the team is actually quite big.
In a community health center.
We've worked hard to integrate behavioral health and dental
health into the community health center model.
And so
where if I was in my private practice,
I'd see some bad teeth and say,
well,
I'll go see a dentist.
Well,
I have a dentist right down the hall who can see somebody right away
and uh take care.
Of the problem for the patient.
Likewise for behavioral health,
uh,
if someone needs counseling,
I have a counselor
readily available and in a private setting and in most other settings,
those services don't exist under one roof,
and this is a place where people can get care for just about everything.
I love the sense of community here this is important
I think to a lot of people
the sense of community,
the sense of belonging,
and you know for people that have
different challenges we all have different challenges it's good for everybody.
You know,
and,
um,
that's,
that's what's important is that we all,
you know,
that we all work together and we all fit in.
It's very impactful to have
a community center
in a community
that takes care of everyone from,
you know,
A to Z.